## Mike Machage

www.mikemachage.tech

Phone:+254707800048

Email: mikemachage@gmail.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a top-performing software engineer and entrepreneur, well-versed in JavaScript technologies such as Node.js, React, Next.js, and TypeScript. I have extensive experience bridging the gap between business and technical departments, effectively translating business needs into technical requirements and analyzing the impact of changes as new solutions are implemented. A strong team player, I excel at communicating project progress to clients, fostering long-lasting business relationships, and ensuring successful outcomes.

#### **RELEVANT SKILLS**

TECHNICAL	NON-TECHNICAL
<ul> <li>Advanced knowledge in Node Js.</li> <li>Web Design &amp; Development</li> <li>Knowledge of databases such as SQL</li> <li>Knowledge of Front-end &amp; Back-end technologies such as React, ShadcnUI NodeJs, NextUI &amp; Js</li> <li>Advanced web optimization</li> <li>Content management systems such as WordPress, Squarespace</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Tutoring</li> <li>Business Analysis</li> <li>Adept knowledge and experience with Agile methodologies</li> <li>Good communication</li> <li>Critical thinker</li> <li>Strong problem-solving skills</li> <li>Exceptional time management</li> </ul>

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **SELF EMPLOYED**

Freelance Software Engineer | July 2024 - Present

#### **GLOXAD ACADEMY**

Freelance Software Engineer | Jan 2024 - June 2024

I worked remotely part-time with a team of Developers as a Front-End developer on <a href="https://www.gloxadacademy.com">www.gloxadacademy.com</a>.

As a Frontend Developer at Gloxad Academy, I worked with a dynamic team committed to building an innovative e-learning platform from scratch. My responsibilities include:

- Designing and Implementing User Interfaces: Using React to develop responsive and intuitive user experiences.

My role was crucial in delivering a high-quality, scalable e-learning solution that meets the needs of both learners and educators.

### **EDUCATION**

YEAR	SCHOOL
2023 - 2024	Holberton School - ALX Africa - Software Engineering
2012 - 2016	University of Eldoret
2008 - 2011	Molo Academy
2002 - 2007	Kenyenya Junior Academy

# INTERESTS Gaming, basketball, reading.